《少年谢尔顿》前情提要
Previously on Young Sheldon...
你们认识洛圣朋先生吗
You know that Mr. Rosenbloom
在牛排馆附近开家具店的那个
with the furniture store over by the steak house?
他约我去共进晚餐
He's asked me to dinner.
他是你男朋友吗
Is he your boyfriend?
是我其中一个  所以别提这方面的事
Well, he's one of them, so let's not bring that up.
好啦  我有何能为你效劳
All right, so what can I do for you?
当犹太人是什么感觉
What's it like to be Jewish?
烂透了  我不建议
Oh, it's terrible. I don't recommend it.
怎么了
Yeah?
康妮  我是想邀请你今晚一起吃饭
Connie, I would like to have dinner with you tonight.
看起来情势一片大好
This is very promising.
斯特吉斯博士和姥姥
Dr. Sturgis and Meemaw
第一次一起过夜了
had their first sleepover.
这是他们恋爱关系的重大进展
It's a big step in their relationship.
我要去恭喜他们
I'm going to go congratulate them.
先穿上外套  外面很冷
Hey, put on a jacket, it's chilly out.
你好像甜点永远都只吃香草冰激凌
I have only seen you eat vanilla ice cream for dessert.
-这是为什么  -我是跟一个
- Why is that? - Well, I've taken a page
伟大的物理学家理查德·费曼学的
from the great physicist Richard Feynman.
为了减少生命中总要下的其中一个决定
In order to have one less decision in his life,
他决定甜点永远只吃巧克力冰激凌
he decided that dessert would always be chocolate ice cream.
感觉有一天会吃腻的吧
Sounds like it could get kind of boring.
的确是
Oh, it does.
但在过去35年间
But over the last 35 years,
我相信我因此省下了起码一天半的生命
I believe I've saved at least a day and a half.
有机会你一定得让我也为你做饭
Well, you have to let me cook for you sometime.
但我很喜欢为你做饭啊
But I enjoy cooking for you.
是我向你表达爱意的一种方式
It's a means of expressing my affection.
而且这样我才能控制菜里放多少大蒜
It also allows me to control the amount of garlic,
因为那会让我打嗝
which gives me the burps.
我做的烤肉超级好吃
Well, I do make a mean barbecue,
我可以保证不放任何大蒜
and I promise I can make it garlic-free.
妙哉
Excellent!
下一次就让你向我表达爱意吧
Next time, you can express your affection for me.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
估计是谢尔顿打来查岗
I bet it's Sheldon checking on us.
干嘛
What?
康妮  我是艾拉
Connie? It's Ira.
我...
I'm, uh...
是谢尔顿
I-It's Sheldon.
他听起来好像有点焦躁
He... sounds a little agitated.
我到旁边去接一下电话
I'm gonna take it in the other room.
稍等...
Just...
你继续说吧
Hello again.
是这样的  我想问一下你周末有没有安排
Listen, I'm wondering what you're doing this weekend.
我想你了
I miss you.
很好  很好
Cool, cool.
想一起去看个电影吗
You want to go to a movie
或者是打几局保龄球
or bowl a few frames?
是这样的  我现在不太方便讲电话
Uh, you know, listen, it's not a great time right now.
我的家人们来我家了
Um, I have a little family over,
我能之后再回电吗
and can I call you later?
好的  抱歉啊  我也不想打扰到你们
Yeah. Yeah, I'm sorry. I-I don't want to interrupt.
我只是有点想念你的声音了
I just miss hearing your voice.
那你现在听到啦
Well... here it is,
从我喉咙产地直发出来的声音
coming right up out of my throat.
好啦
Um, okay,
那...  再见啦
so, uh, uh, bye.
再见
Bye-bye.
谢尔顿怎么样了
How's Sheldon doing?
-什么  -谢尔顿啊
- What? - Sheldon.
你刚才不是跟谢尔顿讲电话吗
You were talking to Sheldon.
对  对的
Oh... right, yes.
你知道他房间里有挂费曼那个人的照片吗
Did you know he has a picture of that fella Feynman in his bedroom?
真的吗  我也是啊
What? So do I.
你们简直是哥俩好
Peas in a pod.
真讨厌
Oh, darn.
再失陪一下
Excuse me.
谁啊
Yes?
情况怎么样了
How's it going?
谢尔顿又打来了
It's Sheldon again.
什么叫"又"打来了
What do you mean "again"?
有话快说
Speak.
我最近读了一个文章
I recently read an article
写到超导超级对撞机
about a superconducting supercollider
有可能要在德州这里建一台
that might be built in Texas.
然后呢
What about it?
我是想到如果你们
Well, I thought if there was a lull
晚餐出现没话题的场面时
in your dinner conversation,
你可以不经意地说出这个来打破冷场
you might casually drop it as an icebreaker.
我们晚餐中间聊得可开心了
Our dinner conversation is going just fine.
现在你又多了一个话题储备
Well, now you have it in your back pocket.
你们继续吧
Carry on.
提问  我们今晚会有交媾行为吗
Question-- will we be engaging in coitus tonight?
因为我好像在骑车来的路上
Because I believe I pulled a hamstring
拉伤了腿筋
on the bike ride over.
那你怎么不早点说呢
Why didn't you say something?
我本来想要表现我的男子气概
Well, I was trying to display machismo,
但我鼠蹊部之间的疼痛
but it's becoming more and more clear
越来越强烈地在表示我真的伤了
that there's something askew in my groin.
约翰
Oh, John...
不用你费力做什么
we don't have to do anything.
我们可以就待着啊
We can just be together.
谢谢
Thanks.
但如果你无所谓的话
But if it's all the same to you,
我还是想拼一把试试看
I'd like to give it the old college try.
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
给
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以你真的要
So, you're really gonna go out
一边跟这个家具店的男人好
with this furniture store fella
一边也跟斯特吉斯博士交往吗
while seeing Dr. Sturgis?
我这叫游戏人间
It's called playing the field.
如果你也像我一样玩过
And if you'd done some of that,
或许你就不会跟里面那位"布鲁托"好上了
you wouldn't be saddled with Bluto in there.
动画《大力水手》中的经典角色  身材魁梧
这话太坏了吧
That's not nice.
而且你有必要这么加吗
And is that really necessary?
意大利人把这个叫"卡瑞托[改正确]"
The Italians call it "Corretto."
意思就是把饮料给改对了
It means correcting the drink.
所以不加酒精的饮品就是错误的吗
So, a drink without alcohol in it is wrong?
没错
Yep.
意大利人可懂行了
Italian people, they know what's up.
行吧  你的问题一次解决一个
All right, one issue at a time.
所以你真的要脚踏两条船吗
So, you're really gonna date two men simultaneously?
-这两个是你知道的部分  -妈
- Two that you know of. - Oh, Mom.
干嘛啦  别这么死板
Come on, don't be such a prude.
我又不会有小孩
I'm not gonna have any babies.
我也不需要这些男人养我
I don't need these men to take care of me.
我为什么不好好享受人生呢
Why shouldn't I just enjoy myself?
因为这样很对不起神啊
Well, it isn't very Christian of you.
这个我无从反驳
I got no argument there.
敬你一杯
Salute!
这饮料果然救回来了
Yeah, that fixed it.
姥姥  别啊
Oh, Meemaw, no.
你在打给谁
Hey, who are you calling?
斯特吉斯博士
Dr. Sturgis.
为什么
Why?
我看到姥姥上了洛圣朋先生的车
I saw Meemaw get in a car with Mr. Rosenbloom.
别啊
No...
我不知道是不是真的这么发生了
I don't know if it really happened this way,
但是在九岁的我的眼中
but to my nine-year-old mind,
我妈当时飞起来了
my mother was flying.
这牛胸怎么样
So, how's the brisket?
不错
It's good.
虽然没我做的好吃  但还不错
It ain't my brisket, but it's good.
我应该带你去纽约
I should take you to New York
这样你就能尝到正宗的犹太牛胸肉了
so you could taste some authentic Jewish brisket.
会有什么不一样呢
How's it different?
基本上大同小异啦
Well, it's pretty much the same except
只不过是会比较多汁  而且你可以感觉到
it's-it's a lot juicier and you can feel the fat
脂肪直接往你心脏灌
go directly to your heart.
天啊
Oh, boy...
我好想念你这笑声啊
I miss that laugh.
所以...
So, uh...
你觉得这主意如何
what do you think of that idea?
-什么主意  -一起去纽约
- What idea? - Going to New York.
或许我们还能看几个百老汇音乐剧
Maybe we'll catch a couple of Broadway shows,
去看些风景
uh, see some sights.
艾拉  这个...
Oh, Ira, gee...
我不知道了
I don't know.
-感觉是很大一步的进展  -会吗
- Seems like a big step. ?- Is it?
我觉得活到我们这个岁数了
I think at this time of our lives,
我们应该多旅游  去看看世界
we should travel, see the world.
-大概吧  -说到底
- I guess. - I mean,
我们也不会越活越年轻
we're not getting any younger.
你这话是几个意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我的意思是我渐渐不年轻了
I mean, I mean, I'm not getting any younger.
但你跟我不一样
You, on the other hand,
你还是朵绽放的郁金香
you are a blossoming tulip.
这还差不多
Better.
但我无法不理解
But I still don't understand.
你的外祖母是个单身女士
Your grandmother's a single lady.
她还没有跟任何一位男士定下来
She's not committed to any one fella,
她想多看看自己还有那些男人可选
and she wants to see what her options are.
可是斯特吉斯博士就是最好的选择
But Dr. Sturgis is the best option.
或许你是这么觉得
Well, you might feel that way,
但是她还没下定决心呢
but she's not so sure.
那我们得告诉她啊  我去打电话
Then we need to tell her. I'll make the call.
不行  我们不该多管闲事
No. We need to mind our business
我们就祈祷她会做出正确选择吧
and maybe pray for her to make the right decision.
我们要把命运交到上帝的手里吗
We're gonna leave this up to God?
你觉得你能做得比上帝更好吗
You think you could do a better job than God?
或许在创世上比不上他的
Maybe not with creating the universe,
但我觉得我用一场瘟疫
but I bet I could free the Hebrews
就能在解放希伯来人上强过祂
with one good plague.
你可以在清晨3点半
You can get lox, bagels,
吃到熏鲑鱼贝果加各式配料呢
all the trimmings at 3:30 in the morning.
我为什么会想要那个
Why would I want that?
的确是不会  太正餐了
Well, you wouldn't. I mean, it's too heavy.
但只要你想吃就能吃得到
But you could if you wanted.
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
艾拉  我觉得不行
Oh, Ira, I don't think so.
好吧  那这样吧
All right, what do you say
去新奥尔良过一个周末如何
to a weekend in New Orleans, huh?
我们可以去坐那种高级游轮之类的
We could do one of those Carnival Cruise things.
我要被你逼疯了
You're killing me.
我没办法  我...
I can't do this, I...
你没办法什么
Can't do what?
艾拉  你是个好人
Ira, you're just a wonderful man.
天啊  我可不喜欢你这句话的走向
Oh, boy, I don't like where this is going.
但我得跟你实话实说
But to tell you the truth,
我有跟别人交往
I'm seeing somebody else.
一刀毙命
And we've gone there.
我本来想我可以做到  同时跟你们交往
I thought I could do it, uh... you know, date both of you,
但我做不到  我做不来...
but I-I can't, I can't, I just...
我就不是这块料
I'm not cut out for it.
好吧  我有个提议
Okay, suggestion.
或许你可能也想过这个想法了
And maybe you've already thought of this...
你觉得你去跟那个人分手
but what do you say you break up with him
然后只跟我交往如何
and only see me?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我以为我能承受
I thought I could handle this.
-没事啦  -你知道吗
- It's okay. - You know,
当你年纪渐长  你以为自己会脸皮更厚
you get older, and you think your skin is thicker...
-没事的  -更不容易伤心
- It's okay. - ...and your heart is tougher.
但其实并不是这样  事实恰恰相反
But it's not, it's the other way around.
希望那个男的知道自己捡到什么样的宝了
I hope this guy knows what a gift he has in you.
"宝"这个词有点过了吧
Well, "gift" is a strong word,
但他对我很上心啦
but he's enthusiastic.
那很好
Good.
祝你们两个快快乐乐
May you both be very happy together!
我不想太快就开始庆祝
I don't want to celebrate too soon,
但姥姥从洛圣朋先生车上下来  他在哭
but Meemaw and Mr. Rosenbloom are back, and he was crying.
有更新消息我会再来分享
There'll be more updates as they happen.
我吃完了
I'm done.
我能请求提早离桌吗
Can I please be excused?
天啊  你有没有嚼啊
Good Lord, did you even chew it?
没有嚼到医生建议次数
Not the recommended amount, no.
你这么着急要干嘛
What's your hurry?
我得回到我的观察位
I need to get back to my viewing post.
行  你去吧
Fine, go ahead.
他这么盯着姥姥的家是想看到什么啊
What's he expect to see, staring at Meemaw's house?
你刚进我们家吗
Did you just join this family?
那孩子就是个怪胎
The kid's an oddball.
他只是对姥姥跟一个
He's just excited that Meemaw's dating
他所敬仰的人交往而感到兴奋
a man he looks up to.
我希望她可以跟托尼·丹扎约会  那才酷呢
I wish she could date Tony Danza-- that'd be cool.
你到底是在迷托尼·丹扎哪里啊
What is it with you and Tony Danza?
虽然电视剧里没说也没演出来
Well, the show doesn't come out and say it,
但我敢肯定他是老大
but I'm pretty sure he's the boss.
我觉得那金发妞才是老大
I think the blonde lady's the boss.
安琪拉吗
Angela?
现在谁才是怪胎
Who's the oddball now?
我可警告你
I'm warning you,
一旦你尝了我做的烤肉
once you try my barbecue,
其他人做的你再也看不上眼
it will ruin you to all the others.
这跟我当初开始用高档厕纸一样
That's what happened to me with quilted toilet paper.
一旦我试过了好东西
Once I tried the good stuff,
其他用起来都像钢丝球
everything else felt like a Brillo pad.
你的比喻可真有画面感啊
You paint quite the picture, don't you?
天啊
Oh, gosh.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
谢尔顿  这可一点也不可爱了
Sheldon, this is not cute anymore.
康妮·塔克
Connie Tucker?
是我
Yes?
洛圣朋家具店的餐桌椅送到了
I have a dinette set from Rosenbloom's Furniture.
我没买家具啊
I didn't buy any furniture.
应该是别人送给你的礼物
I think it's a gift.
老天
Oh, boy.
我弯腰捡一本书
I bent down to pick up a book,
她不趁机偷看我屁股才奇了怪呢
and I'll be darned if she didn't sneak a look at my derriere.
这家伙
Oh, man.
你们肯定不敢相信姥姥家刚发生了什么
You won't believe what's happening at Meemaw's house.
比《成长没烦恼[谁才是老大]》更有趣吗
Is it more interesting than Who's the Boss?
我深表怀疑
Doubt it.
洛圣朋家具店  我是艾拉
Rosenbloom's Fine Furniture. Ira speaking.
你为什么送家具给我
Why are you sending me furniture?
我决定不要这么悄然离开
I've decided I can't go away quietly.
我要争取你的爱
I'm fighting for your love.
用一套餐桌椅吗
With a dinette set?
这可不是普通的餐桌椅  这是我们最热销的款式
Oh, this isn't just any dinette set. It's our biggest seller.
而且不是复合板材哦
And it's not pressed wood--
是纯橡木的
it's oak!
艾拉  我不喜欢这样
Ira, I don't like this.
还是你更喜欢皮革面料的
Would you prefer a leather sectional?
发生什么事了
Uh, what's going on?
我晚点再打给你好吗
Can I call you back?
期待你的来电
I look forward to it.
别瞎期待
You shouldn't.
好吧
Okay.
我猜可以这么说
I guess you could say
我其中一位前男友
one of my former boyfriends
试图用家具赢回我的心
is trying to win me back with furniture.
真厉害
Huh. Impressive.
这可是真橡木
This is real oak.
刚才电话里的是他吗
Was that him on the phone?
是的  很抱歉
Yes. I'm sorry.
有意思
Interesting.
什么
What?
知道有另一个男人跟我抢你
Being challenged by another man
你对我的吸引力立刻大增
is making you more attractive to me.
我没听懂
I don't follow.
我得做些研究
I'll have to do some research,
但我猜这是藏在基因里的本能
but I'm guessing this is a genetic instinct
让我性欲大增啊
that's raising my libido.
我要来一杯
I need a drink.
你们能相信他居然想用一组餐桌椅赢回我的心
Can you believe he tried to win me back with a dinette set?
如果你离开德州  我立刻送你一套餐桌椅
I'd give you a dinette set if you'd leave Texas.
那你会把东西退回去吗
So, would you return it?
当然不会  我要留着
Hell no, I'm keeping it.
可这样就等于欠人家一份情
But then you'll be beholden to him.
你有可能跟艾拉复合吗
Would you ever take Ira back?
我不知道
I don't know.
他很体贴很暖  但...
He's sweet as he can be, but...
约翰就是不一样
there's just something about John.
他就像一只可爱的小泰迪熊
He's like a cute little teddy bear, you know?
一只聪明
A brilliant,
会骑自行车的
bicycle-riding
泰迪熊
teddy bear.
他说的话有一半我都听不懂
I don't even understand half of what he says.
可是...
But...
当他不在身边  我就格外想他
when he's not around, I just miss him.
听上去你恋爱了
Sounds like you're falling in love.
或许是的
Maybe I am.
太棒了  我也爱他
Excellent. I love him, too.
给我出去
Get out of here!
如果你不懂斯特吉斯博士说什么
If you don't understand what Dr. Sturgis says,
我很乐意为你解释
I'm happy to explain it to you.
滚
Get!
打扰了
Excuse me.
我想找艾拉
I'm looking for Ira.
乐意为你效劳  有什么可以帮你的吗
At your service. What can I do for you?
先生  你越界了
You, sir, have overstepped your bounds.
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
康斯坦丝·塔克小姐
Miss Constance Tucker
曾清楚向你表示  不再接受你任何形式的求爱
made it clear your courtship was no longer welcome,
而你的回应却是六张椅子
and you responded with six chairs,
一张桌子和一张大活动桌板
a table, and an expansion leaf.
你是哪根葱
Who are you?
约翰·斯特吉斯
John Sturgis,
她最终选择的男人
the man she chose
你的情敌
and your romantic rival.
抱歉  你找我到底想干什么
I-I'm sorry, wait, what-what is it you want from me?
我想要你放弃追求康妮
I want you to give up your pursuit of Connie.
好吧  现在请你离开我的店铺
All right, I'm gonna have to ask you to leave my store.
非常好
Very well.
分界线已划
The line in the sand has been drawn.
越界有风险
Cross it at your own peril.
怪胎
Weirdo.
你刚说什么
What was that?
你明明听见了
You heard me.
先生  我是一个有感情的人
Sir, I am a man with feelings.
你伤害到我感情了
And you have hurt them.
我知道你有过很多...
I know you've had a number of...
男性访客
gentleman callers,
但我从没听你用这样的语气说起过任何一个人
but I've never heard you speak like this before.
"男性访客"
"Gentleman callers"?
我们还好奇谢尔顿在哪儿学来这个词的
And we wonder where Sheldon gets it.
抱歉你们俩觉得好笑
I'm sorry y'all find this funny,
但这是自从我爸去世后
but this is the first time
我妈第一次对一个男人
my mother's expressed real interest in a man
表达出有兴趣
since Dad died.
原谅我想了解更多
Forgive me for wanting to know more.
你真的想了解更多吗
You really want to know more?
想象一下你们俩都上了年纪
Imagine you're getting on in years,
你和你老公准备退休
you and your husband about to retire,
在萨拉索塔搞了个分时度假
get a little timeshare in Sarasota,
而猝不及防
and... suddenly...
他去世了
he's gone,
只留下你一个人
and you're all alone.
你忧伤你哭泣
You mourn, you cry,
但最终你要往前看
but eventually you move on.
于是你开始约会
You start dating a little,
发现还挺好玩
and it's all good fun.
但你内心深处总有一个声音
But always in the back of your mind,
在问同一个问题
there's that question...
"我会孤独终老吗"
"Will I be alone in the end?"
你们俩看我干嘛啦
Why y'all looking at me for?
我好几天没睡觉
Haven't slept in days.
感觉我就像一个为情所困的青少年
It's like I'm a lovesick teenager,
哈里·S·杜鲁门  1945年任美国第33任总统
除了我记得杜鲁门政府
except I remember the Truman administration.
你的感受都是可以理解
Your feelings are understandable.
康妮是一个了不起的女性
Connie is a remarkable woman.
的确
Yes, she is.
再次道歉  我不该叫你怪胎
But, again, I'm sorry. I should never have called you weird.
我知道  这很无礼
I mean, eh, it was rude.
我还有过更无礼的称呼
I've been called much worse.
一位教授称我为奇葩
A professor once called me ostrobogulous.
我还得查词典找这个词
I had to look that one up.
那是什么意思
What's it mean?
也是怪胎的意思
That I'm a weirdo.
约翰  你是一个好人
John, you're a great guy.
你也是
Well, you, too!
但我希望你明白  我只是...
But I hope you understand, I just...
我不能放弃康妮
I can't give up on Connie.
没关系
That's all right.
跟你说句实话
To tell you the truth,
我发现竞争令人兴奋
I'm finding the competition quite exhilarating.
你真这么觉得吗
You are?
是的
Oh, yes.
那套餐桌椅送来的那晚
The night the dinette set arrived,
我做了我40年来第一次俯卧撑
I did my first push-up in 40 years.
抱歉  但我觉得这真是...
I'm sorry, but I find that to be, uh--
那个词是什么来着  奇八吗
what's the word-- astro-boobulous?
奇葩
Ostrobogulous.
没错
Exactly.
现在给我来个最优惠的价格
Now, give me your best price
我要买一张这个
on one of these
要有杯托的哦
with a cup holder.
约翰  真是意外之喜啊
John! What a pleasant surprise.
我有件事要告诉你
I have some news for you.
什么事
What is that?
我去了家具店跟艾拉聊了聊
I went to the furniture store and spoke to Ira.
你为什么要这么做
Why would you do that?
要求他尊重你的请求  别再烦你
To demand that he respect your wish to be left alone.
约翰  你没有资格去做这种事
John, it was not your place to do that.
那这点可能安慰到你
Well, if it helps,
他不打算离开你
he doesn't plan on leaving you alone.
你到底在想什么啊
What the hell were you thinking?!
我是想发挥骑士精神嘛
That I was being chivalrous.
背着我干这种事算吗
By going behind my back?
你看起来不爽啊
You seem upset.
我是不爽
I am upset!
我怎么处理艾拉是我的事
And how I handle Ira is my business!
我希望你能温柔点
Well, I hope you do it gently.
他现在非常脆弱
He's very vulnerable these days.
你们现在还成朋友了吗
You're friends now?
现在我不敢这么说
Well, I wouldn't say friends,
但我可以预见  长此以往
but I could see, over time,
我们很可能...
you know, we might...
你们俩是在吵架吗
Are you two fighting?
不是
No.
太好了
Oh, good.
我差点以为我们是在吵架
I was almost certain that we were.
就是
We are.
-我迷糊了  -我也是
- I'm confused. - Me, too.
是因为你去家具店那件事吗
Is this because you went to the furniture store?
他也知道这事吗
He knows about this?
是的  -好了  给我听好了
- Yes. - All right, now, listen,
如果这段感情还想有任何可能性
if this relationship's gonna have any chance at all,
我们必须立下基本规矩
we have to lay down some ground rules.
太棒了  我爱规矩
Great. I love rules.
我也是
I do, too.
我不想你再跟他说任何
I don't want you talking to him about anything
关于我们的事情
having to do with anything about us.
你也是
Same with you.
我要你立刻停止
And I want you to stop
用你的望远镜监视我
spying on me with those binoculars
就好像你在进行什么非洲狩猎旅行一样
like you're on some kind of African safari.
你不能跟艾拉说话
And you cannot talk to Ira
或者我任何前男友你都不该去聊这个
or any of my ex-boyfriends, for that matter.
规矩越来越多
This list is getting long.
或许我们该写下来
Maybe we should write it down.
在那一刻
In that moment,
我突然顿悟
I had an epiphany.
我可以为任何社交关系拟订合同
I could draw up a contract for any social relationship.
在这个经常讲不清道不明的世界里
It was a helpful way to remove ambiguity
这是一种消除模棱两可的话的有效方式
in a world that was often hard to understand.
条目三
Article three--
谢尔顿不准
Sheldon will not spy
用望远镜监视姥姥家
on Meemaw's house with binoculars.
这句话给我加粗
Type that one in bold.
请签上姓名和日期
Please sign and date.
谢尔顿  如果有帮助的话  我还有公证人资格
You know, Sheldon, I'm a notary, if that helps.
你在我心目中的形象变得更酷了
Just when I thought you couldn't get cooler.
我决定
I would go on
这辈子都会继续拟定合同的行为
to draw up such contracts throughout my life--
无论是跟室友
with roommates,
还是妻子
with my wife.
甚至是跟我的孩子们
Even with my own children.